<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jadflix</title>
    <description>Jadflix - the center of Jaden&apos;s Latin HW.  Based on the Jekflix template.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 22:54:31 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 22:54:31 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Frangens Malum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Jadflix ferunt tibi Frangens Malum
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/breakingbad.png&quot; alt=&quot;Breaking Bad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 13:04:18 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/breakingbad/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/breakingbad/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Peregriniores Res</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fratres Duffer ferunt tibi Peregriniores Res
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/strangerthings.png&quot; alt=&quot;Stranger Things&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 13:04:18 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/strangerthings/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/strangerthings/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote 5 - Section A</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the quote “Ab Antōniō, alterō cōnsule, Catilīna ipse victus proeliō est interfectus.” Eutropius gives an example of the justice meted out to those who go against Rome. The section starts with a description of Cataline and his intentions against Rome, but after just a few sentences, Cataline’s supporters are executed and Cataline himself is defeated and killed. This short separation between treason and death gives the reader a strong motivation for loyalty to Rome and an idea of the fate that lies for those who are against Rome. This was important given Emperor Valens’ paranoia against his enemies (and...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 12:36:58 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/fifth/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/fifth/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote 4 - Section D</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Eutropius warns Valens to not get to arrogant in the quote “Cum ergō et honōrēs ex suā voluntāte praestāret, quī ā populō anteā dēferēbantur, nec senātuī ad sē venientī adsurgeret aliaque rēgia ac paene tyrannica faceret, coniūrātum est in eum ā sexāgintā vel amplius senātōribus equitibusque Rōmānīs.” Although Valens is the all-powerful emperor in the Roman Empire, even Caesar, as great as he was and the dictator for life, was killed for acting arrogantly. Although Caesar’s situation was obviously different from Valens’ with the senate and his many powerful political enemies, Eutropius’ point still stands - by acting arrogantly -...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 12:35:39 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/fourth/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/fourth/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote 3 - Section C</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Eutropius highlights the greatness of the men in the late Republic and the beginning of the empire - especially that of Pompey and Caesar. In the quote “Numquam adhūc Rōmanae cōpiae in ūnum neque maiōrēs neque meliōribus ducibus convēnerant, tōtum terrārum orbem facile subāctūrae, sī contrā barbarōs dūcerentur.”, Eutropius refers to Pompey and Caesar as the greatest leaders leading the largest armies, easily able to conquer the whole world. This praise of Pompey and Caesar reinforces the idea of Rome’s past great leaders to the reader and the description of the strength of their armies reinforces the idea of Rome’s...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 12:34:09 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/third/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/third/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote 2 - Section B</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Eutropius portrays the Republic as great in his Breviarium, as evidenced by the quote: “Hinc iam bellum civile successit exsecrandum et lacrimabile, quo praeter calamitates, quae in proeliis acciderunt, etiam populi Romani fortuna mutata est.” He describes the civil war, a pivotal moment turning away from the Republic as accursed and lamentable, and says that the calamities in battle were only surpassed by the change in fortune for the Roman people. Eutropius’ negative description of the civil war and his stated belief that the change for the Roman people was a “calamity” sends a clear message to the reader for...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 12:32:21 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/second/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/second/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote 1 - Section A</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In his Breviarium, Eutropius puts focus onto the glory that can be acquired through expansion. Eutropius writes: “Domuit autem annis novem fere omnem Galliam, quae inter Alpes, flumen Rhodanum, Rhenum et Oceanum est et circuitu patet ad bis et tricies centena milia passuum.” His positive view of conquest is clear in his lengthy and almost poetic description of the size of Caesar’s conquest, and his inclusion of how Caesar only took 9 years to achieve this great feat. Eutropius uses this glorification of conquest and the great men who expanded Rome to encourage emperor Valens to continue to expand the...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 12:27:40 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/first/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/first/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
