<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jadflix</title>
    <description>Jadflix - the center of Jaden&apos;s Latin HW.  Based on the Jekflix template.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 20:35:06 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 20:35:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Republic to Empire Timeline Summary</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our roadmap project, created by both of us and Troy and Ben, and Eutropius’ Breviarium share many historical events. Eutropius and we wrote about events, such as the Battle of Atrium and the murder of Caesar, and historically significant people, such as Crassus, Octavian, Pompey, and Cleopatra. However, we differed in the time range and focus. In the excerpts we’ve seen, Eutropius wrote about more focused topics, seen in the many civil wars, which we also wrote about, between Octavian, Antony, and many other characters that he mainly wrote about based on the excerpts. We wrote about broader topics, such...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:04:28 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/eutropius_timeline_summary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/eutropius_timeline_summary/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Republic to Empire Timeline 10</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With everything said and done, Egypt was added to the new Roman Empire and given a Roman govenor.  “Aegyptus per Octavianum Augustum imperio Romano adiecta est praepositusque ei C. Cornelius Gallus. Hunc primum Aegyptus Romanum iudicem habuit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/eutropius_timeline_10.png&quot; alt=&quot;Breaking Bad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:04:27 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/eutropius_timeline_10/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/eutropius_timeline_10/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Republic to Empire Timeline 9</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After being defeated, Antony and Cleopatra killed themselves, leaving no opposition to Octavian’s rise to emperor.  “Desperatis rebus, cum omnes ad Augustum transirent, [Antonius] ipse se interemit. Cleopatra sibi aspidem admisit et veneno eius exstincta est.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/eutropius_timeline_9.png&quot; alt=&quot;Breaking Bad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:04:26 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/eutropius_timeline_9/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/eutropius_timeline_9/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Republic to Empire Timeline 8</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Egged on by Cleopatra, Antony stirs up a civil war against Octavian.  However, he is defeated at the battle of Actium, leaving Caesar as the most powerful man in Rome.  “Hic quoque ingens bellum civile commovit cogente uxore Cleopatra… dum cupiditate muliebri optat etiam in urbe regnare. Victus est ab Augusto navali pguna clara et illustri apud Actium.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/eutropius_timeline_8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Breaking Bad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:04:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/eutropius_timeline_8/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/eutropius_timeline_8/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Republic to Empire Timeline 7</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Antony divorces Octavian’s sister and marries Cleopatra, sowing the seeds for another civil war.  “Antonius… repudiata sorore Caesaris Augusti Octaviani, Cleopatram, reginam Aegypti, duxit uxorem.”
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/eutropius_timeline_7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Breaking Bad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:04:24 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/eutropius_timeline_7/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/eutropius_timeline_7/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Republic to Empire Timeline 6</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Bassus defeats the Parthian tribes, kills the son of the killer of Crassus, and celebrates his victory.  Eutropius describes this in the quote “Pacorum, regis Orodis filium, interfecit eo ipso die quo olim Orodes, Persarum rex, per ducem Surenam Crassum occiderat. Hib primus de Parthis iustissimum triumphum Romae egit.”
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/eutropius_timeline_6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Breaking Bad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:04:23 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/eutropius_timeline_6/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/eutropius_timeline_6/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Republic to Empire Timeline 5</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With all the challengers to their power removed and the senate gone, Antony and Octavian split the republic between themselves.  This is described in the quote “Ac sic inter eos divisa est res publica.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/eutropius_timeline_5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Breaking Bad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:04:22 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/eutropius_timeline_5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/eutropius_timeline_5/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Republic to Empire Timeline 4</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Brutus and Cassius start a huge civil war against Octavian and Antony, but are defeated, removing most of the challengers to the 2nd Triumvirate.  Although Octavian and Caesar are defeated at first in the Battle of Philippi, Cassius dies, and Brutus and the rest of the nobles are killed soon after.  This is described in the quote “Profecti sunt igitur contra eos Caesar Octavianus Augustus et M. Antonius… secundo  Brutum et infinitam nobilitatem… victam interfecerunt.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/eutropius_timeline_4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image #4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:04:21 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/eutropius_timeline_4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/eutropius_timeline_4/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Republic to Empire Timeline 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Octavian, Lepidus, and Antony take over the Republic forcefully and get rid of the senate (a crucial part of the Roman Republic)
“Senatum proscripsit, cum Antonio ac Lepido rem publicam armis tenere coepit.”
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/eutropius_timeline_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image #3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:04:20 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/eutropius_timeline_3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/eutropius_timeline_3/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Republic to Empire Timeline 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Octavian leads an army to Rome and demands a consulship, giving him more power and weakening the authority of the senate by forcing them to do things in a very undemocratic fashion. This is described by Eutropius in the quote “Romam cum exercitu profectus extorsit ut sibi vicesimo anno consulatus daretur.”
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/eutropius_timeline_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Breaking Bad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:04:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/eutropius_timeline_2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/eutropius_timeline_2/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Republic to Empire Timeline 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Antony flees to Lepidus, and through Lepidus, Antony, Octavian, and Lepidus band together to form the 2nd Triumvirate, which gives Octavian more power and helps him on his way to emperor. Lepidus’ role in saving Antony and bringing Antony and Octavian together is seen in the quote ““Fugatus Antonius, amisso exercitu, confugit ad Lepidum… . Mox, Lepido operam dante, Caesar pacem cum Antonio fecit…” “
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/eutropius_timeline_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image #1&quot; /&gt;
https://thedailyjournalist.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/tri-3.jpg&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 13:04:18 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/eutropius_timeline_1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/eutropius_timeline_1/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Frangens Malum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Jadflix ferunt tibi Frangens Malum
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/breakingbad.png&quot; alt=&quot;Breaking Bad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 13:04:18 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/breakingbad/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/breakingbad/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Peregriniores Res</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fratres Duffer ferunt tibi Peregriniores Res
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/strangerthings.png&quot; alt=&quot;Stranger Things&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 13:04:18 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/strangerthings/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/strangerthings/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote 5 - Section A</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the quote “Ab Antōniō, alterō cōnsule, Catilīna ipse victus proeliō est interfectus.” Eutropius gives an example of the justice meted out to those who go against Rome. The section starts with a description of Cataline and his intentions against Rome, but after just a few sentences, Cataline’s supporters are executed and Cataline himself is defeated and killed. This short separation between treason and death gives the reader a strong motivation for loyalty to Rome and an idea of the fate that lies for those who are against Rome. This was important given Emperor Valens’ paranoia against his enemies (and...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 12:36:58 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/fifth/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/fifth/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote 4 - Section D</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Eutropius warns Valens to not get to arrogant in the quote “Cum ergō et honōrēs ex suā voluntāte praestāret, quī ā populō anteā dēferēbantur, nec senātuī ad sē venientī adsurgeret aliaque rēgia ac paene tyrannica faceret, coniūrātum est in eum ā sexāgintā vel amplius senātōribus equitibusque Rōmānīs.” Although Valens is the all-powerful emperor in the Roman Empire, even Caesar, as great as he was and the dictator for life, was killed for acting arrogantly. Although Caesar’s situation was obviously different from Valens’ with the senate and his many powerful political enemies, Eutropius’ point still stands - by acting arrogantly -...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 12:35:39 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/fourth/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/fourth/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote 3 - Section C</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Eutropius highlights the greatness of the men in the late Republic and the beginning of the empire - especially that of Pompey and Caesar. In the quote “Numquam adhūc Rōmanae cōpiae in ūnum neque maiōrēs neque meliōribus ducibus convēnerant, tōtum terrārum orbem facile subāctūrae, sī contrā barbarōs dūcerentur.”, Eutropius refers to Pompey and Caesar as the greatest leaders leading the largest armies, easily able to conquer the whole world. This praise of Pompey and Caesar reinforces the idea of Rome’s past great leaders to the reader and the description of the strength of their armies reinforces the idea of Rome’s...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 12:34:09 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/third/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/third/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote 2 - Section B</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Eutropius portrays the Republic as great in his Breviarium, as evidenced by the quote: “Hinc iam bellum civile successit exsecrandum et lacrimabile, quo praeter calamitates, quae in proeliis acciderunt, etiam populi Romani fortuna mutata est.” He describes the civil war, a pivotal moment turning away from the Republic as accursed and lamentable, and says that the calamities in battle were only surpassed by the change in fortune for the Roman people. Eutropius’ negative description of the civil war and his stated belief that the change for the Roman people was a “calamity” sends a clear message to the reader for...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 12:32:21 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/second/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/second/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote 1 - Section A</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In his Breviarium, Eutropius puts focus onto the glory that can be acquired through expansion. Eutropius writes: “Domuit autem annis novem fere omnem Galliam, quae inter Alpes, flumen Rhodanum, Rhenum et Oceanum est et circuitu patet ad bis et tricies centena milia passuum.” His positive view of conquest is clear in his lengthy and almost poetic description of the size of Caesar’s conquest, and his inclusion of how Caesar only took 9 years to achieve this great feat. Eutropius uses this glorification of conquest and the great men who expanded Rome to encourage emperor Valens to continue to expand the...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 12:27:40 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/first/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/first/</guid>
        
        <category>Eutropius</category>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
